is something that's keeping the stock
alive in the session all right Vivek
thank you very much for that uh that
sadani enterprises buzzing and buzzing
how pretty strong by the way the market
also picked up the Nifty is up 30 points
and that's as good as it gets at least
in today's session so far because it's
not done too much for the bulk of the
day it's this uh up four three down uh
so very very flat for the majority of
the day and there is a bit of Attraction
which is developing as we speak 0.15
percent higher uh 1250 stocks are higher
and you got about almost actually you
know 970 stocks which are lower so there
is enough on both sides but if you want
to see you know the number of stocks
moving on volumes and the advantage has
been for uh has has been with the bulls
on the gaining side for many many uh
weeks now and I think that is no
different today as well prakash thank
you very much great to have you with us
here on the program as always have a
good weekend and we'll see you back next
week let's welcome in Rajesh kothari
managing director of alpha accurate
advisors Rajesh good to have you with us
here welcome back thank you very much so
just a quick word Rajesh if you've
managed to or had a chance to look at
how aggregate earnings are progressing
well into the second quarter earnings
because I was looking at some numbers
and at least aggregate earnings are
coming off you know by some three four
five percent
I'm talking about not growth over 22 but
where 23 expectations were and where
they are now uh what is your sense
right I think uh you know Rakesh so
first of all thanks uh you know for
having me here I think it is a mixed bag
kind of thing because if you look at if
you if you do the Commodities then of
course Commodities are going to kind of
a disappointment in the second quarter
so if you look at further entire the oil
pack or the entire commodity pack the
metal pack the steel pack that are
basically going to do the you know kind
of a more of a downward Trend uh and
that was basically probably expected if
you ask my personal review uh but if you
look at the non-commodity space for
example banking uh most of the large
banks have already announced the results
of course SBI everybody's waiting for
tomorrow but till now the banking has
done reasonably well look at the
advances growth look at the nii growth
look at the asset quality par and large
broadly this sector was expected to
contribute maximum to the Nifty
incremental growth so banking is very
very crucial sector for fy23 and there
the results are in line or little bit
better you know some surprise here or
that if you look at the automobiles
again results are brought in line you
know the maruti is one company of code
which we hold in our portfolio results
are pretty okay and uh you know with
good guidance going forward the waiting
book is still quite quite strong so that
numbers are also fine the capital goods
segment is one segment again many
companies have reported in this segment
and there also if you look at the
revenue growth the execution the order
book broadly again these numbers are in
line I.T uh I think everybody's focusing
on
next two quarters rather than the second
quarter so while the numbers are in line
probably there is a little bit a
downwind kind of a tone and that
basically makes Mark a little bit
worried so by and large x Commodities
and that's how always you should look at
a Nifty earnings uh they are broadly in
line uh compared to Street estimates all
right hi Rajesh uh you know I wanted to
ask you about this other Factor
everyone's talking about Urban India
doing well per rural India is not doing
so well do you think uh you know we
shouldn't Focus so much on how how the
economy is faring you know they should
there I mean it should be pretty much in
line but there shouldn't be a large
disparity is that power for the course
I'm not too sure I think at times we get
really uh you know too much Micro Focus
rural urban it's very very difficult to
actually now differentiate between rural
and urban and every company has their
own definitions you know so fmct company
like you really were definition might be
completely different than if you talk
with HDFC and they are experiencing
housing loan disbursement but for that
matter you know South Base you know
entire banking space the numbers have
been quite good so I think the Beyond a
point one should not worry too much
about rural versus Urban if you look at
the agree growth the tractor's demand
grows the reasonably strong numbers even
in tractors what we can see I think what
has changed you know Nigel is where
people are spending it is less to do
with rural versus Urban it is more to do
with where people want to spend more so
even if you go to the remote place is
you will not get a hotel room maybe you
know so I think that's how the spending
patterns are becoming more important
rather than which segment one should
focus on
no absolutely uh you know one of the
areas and we discussed this last time
you were in the program Rajesh was
cement where you said baby things will
improve cement actually is one of the
sectors which is seen the maximum
earnings downgrade uh do you reckon
maybe the bulk of this is behind uh for
that space Rajesh
yeah I think you know as we discussed
last time and if you look at the stock
performance it's been quite uh you know
we are holding one or two names uh you
know actually only one name and that
company is doing absolutely very well
now that the focus is they on
incremental basis how is your power cost
is moving and that power cost is moving
down so second quarter was always
supposed to be kind of a not that great
quarter uh but the second half is going
to be much stronger and markets are
generally uh at least one or two
quarters ahead of fundamentals so uh you
know I think uh probably one needs to be
very stock specific in cement sector in
particular the raw material because the
the cost side is going to be in your
favor the volume growth will also come
back and that will lead to the better
profitability as we move forward but as
I said uh I think it's better to take a
bottom-up approach when you talk about
cement sector okay all right Rajesh just
hold on to that thought we are getting
uh you know escorts kubota's numbers
that are coming in there and on the top
line it's more or less Inland we have
already had the volumes with us and you
know that indicated that the Top Line
will be strong that's precisely what's
happened however on the march in front
here there appears there's a bit of a
disappointment because we were expecting
margins in double digits and it's coming
at around eight percent odd and that
explains why the stock has come off the
high point of the day as we speak it's
moving towards the days lower just keep
an eye on that the margin Miss is
something that the street will not like
we'll have to wait by for the management
uh you know to clarify and how much of a
recovery can we see from year on well
Rajesh we briefly spoke about Autos uh
from the tractor theme itself uh what
would you play Mahindra and Mahindra has
been a big outperformer unlocking value
as well on the EV side or do you look at
a couple of other names uh maybe an
escorts
no I think you know we are more positive
on a CV cycle and car industry cycle and
auto ancillaries so these are the better
bets in our view uh compared to uh you
know the tractor segment now we believe
that the growth in CV industry as well
as growth in car industry will be
significantly outpaced the growth in
tractor industry
um and also if you look at from the
market share perspective like for in in
for example in car segment so maruti we
expect a lot of new product launches and
that should lead to Improvement is
market share which it lost to its
competition in last two and a half three
years uh similarly in CB space we own
Ashok Leyland and that company is doing
very well you know you see the CV
recovery and the you know monthly
volumes are in front of you
um and the auto engineer is another
space which is very very interesting uh
and there we own companies like kaminda
industry and Craftsman uh and both these
companies are uh you know being
beneficiary of not only domestic
recovery but also uh the opportunity to
export to the world markets
uh you know I think the the
manufacturing space is also of course
that it's capital goods I think we've
discussed in the past defense also the
point is even after the run-up in many
of these defense names you know
valuations P multiples one year forward
bases are still uh 15 17 times
in many ways it's an industry similar to
capital goods right you get you know a
large ordering sort of bunched up
together
uh consistency of ordering is not as
much maybe in other Industries maybe
even less or so as compared to capital
goods also what's your view now Rajesh
because the moves have been so fast here
defense particularly
yeah I think you know your observations
are you know you know broadly right I
think what is more important when you
look at the defense versus other capital
goods companies in defense you get the
you know lumpiness of the order and
those order books are for really long
time so it is not that short cycle
orders it's really the longitude of that
is like 10 years execution 20 years
execution and the earnings growth
therefore is not going to be 30 40
percent uh earnings worth this can be
done 12 percent kind of thing whereas if
you look at the other capital goods
space decide what we own uh of course we
also on defense names but other names
like for example what we is ABB or
cummins or sharflow or this kind of
companies you have a short cycle artist
number one number two these all
companies are of course debt free number
three they have a strong export
opportunities because you know last time
we discussed about you know Europe plus
one which is becoming a new growth
engine for many of these companies so
net net we remain uh you know very very
bullish we talk
we talk team almost I think four
quarters back to a little bit you know
early ahead of the game uh and that is
really rewarding most of these companies
are probably touching their lifetime
highs and now getting consolidating uh
but uh super delivery by this segment
and I think it is just the beginning of
over next three years we continue to see
surprise in order book surprise in order
inflow surprise in revenue and also the
Strong net profit delivery okay all
right Rajesh thanks so much for stopping
by and good to hear that you all have
been early on a couple of these names
like shofla that you said so good going
on that uh thanks so much for joining
and looking forward to chatting up with
you rather soon for the time being
though we'll slip into short break you
come back nimesh is waiting for us on
the other side he'll give us a sneak
peek into what's going on in dealing
rooms we'll also get our technical
experts who'll be back with us to run us
through some closing trades
foreign
[Music]